Finding Aid for Merit Network, Inc. Records, 1966-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Merit Network, Inc. records 1966-2002
Merit Network, Inc.
60 linear feet
05138 Bimu 2
Merit (once an acronym for Michigan Educational Research Information Triad) was an organization developed to research the effects of connecting large research universities together by means of a computer network. Officially established in 1966 and still operating today, Merit contributed greatly to networking and the growth and expansion of the Internet. Most of the materials in the Merit record group documents Merit's early growth and development in the 1960s through Merit's post-NSFNET involvement in the late 1990s. Correspondence, project contracts and proposals, meeting minutes, and administrative records make up the bulk of the records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was transferred through Eric Aupperle, Merit Director, 1974-2001 (Donor No. 9470 ) in two accessions, June and November 2004.
The record group is open without restriction.
Merit (once an acronym for Michigan Educational Research Information Triad) was an organization developed to research the effects of connecting large research universities together by means of a computer network. Officially established in 1966 and still operating today, "Merit is among the Internet pioneers and the oldest organization continuously providing data networking services" (Eric Aupperle Merit--who, what, and why, p.3).
In 1964, Stanford Ericksen, Director of the Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (CRLT) at the University of Michigan, was tasked with writing a proposal for a "state-wide learning center" (Aupperle, p.1) for the Michigan state legislature and asked colleague Karl Zinn to contribute a portion of the proposal to the role of computers in education. Zinn wrote that "significant benefits might be gained from sharing computing resources via an electronic linkage between large, timesharing computers" (Aupperle, p.1). Zinn's small contribution had large implications. As a result, the legislature asked Ericksen and Zinn to study the idea of networking large universities. Wayne State University, Michigan State University, and the University of Michigan formed MICIS, or the Michigan Inter-university Committee on Information Systems, eventually establishing itself as MERIT in 1966.
With a grant from the National Science Foundation (NSF) and indirect project cost support from the University of Michigan (UM agreed to house Merit and pay staff), Merit began to research and build its network. Merit contracted Applied Dynamics Division of Reliance Electric in Saline, Michigan to help build the technology for the network. On December 14, 1971 computers at the University of Michigan and Wayne State University connected for the first time; a connection to Michigan State University was made a year later.
Merit's involvement in the NSF network of national supercomputers, or NSFNET marked an important milestone in Merit's history. In order to manage their ever-expanding network more efficiently and effectively, the NSF solicited proposals for an organization to manage the NSFNET. In November 1987, NSF chose Merit, which had partnered with MCI and IBM to manage its network. Merit, IBM and MCI formed their own company called Advanced Network & Services, Inc. (ANS), which managed this large and sophisticated network, contributing much research and innovation throughout the network's tenure. In 1995, NSF ended its involvement in the NSFNET in favor of commercial vendors. Although Merit no longer managed NSFNET, Merit continued to provide some services for the network after 1995.
Merit has been involved in many different projects and continues to evolve today. For a more in-depth discussion of Merit's history, researchers should consult Eric Aupperle's article on Merit in "Merit--who, what, and why" and John Mulcahy's "A Chronicle of Merit's Early History" (see related resources below for more information). For current Merit projects as of December 2005, researchers can access Merit's website at http://www.merit.edu.
Most of the materials in the Merit record group document Merit's early growth and development in the 1960s through Merit's post-NSFNET involvement in the late 1990s. Correspondence, project contracts and proposals, meeting minutes, and administrative records make up the bulk of the records.
This record group contains the following series: Administrative, Correspondence, Networks, Staff Files, Audiovisual, and Publications.
Subjects:
Merit Network, Inc.; Computer networks--Michigan.; Computers--Michigan.; Information technology.; Education--Data processing.; Corporation for Research and Educational Networking.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; MERIT Computer Network.; Aupperle, Eric M.
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
- Administrative
  The Administrative series (9 linear ft., 1966-2001) documents the administrative aspects of developing and managing Merit, consisting primarily of meeting minutes, contracts, project proposals, finance and budget records, technical memos, and seminars and presentations. Of special note is a historical materials section, assembled by Merit staff that includes key documents in Merit's growth, including Merit's NSF grant and network printouts.
  - Historical Materials
    - Descriptions of Merit 1976 (Box 1)
    - Dedication 1973 (Box 1)
      (includes photographs)
    - MICIS/Merit relationship 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Early history
      (key documents)
      - History and document key (Box 1)
      - Various: speeches, letters, memos, interviews (Box 1)
      - Progress report May 1977 (Box 1)
      - MICIS minutes 1967-1970 (Box 1)
      - NSF grant 1969-1973 (Box 1)
      - State/Merit relations 1966-1972 (Box 1)
      - UM Regents minutes October 1966 (Box 1)
      - First NSF proposal January 1968 (Box 1)
      - Legislative acts 1968-1972 (Box 1)
      - Second NSF proposal December 1968 (Box 1)
      - Hardware selection 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - Merit miscellaneous 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - Memos and administrative material 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - MICIS minutes January 1971-May 1973 (Box 1)
      - Printouts from network tests (Box 1)
      - Issues of On-line,1972-1973 (Box 1)
        (a complete run can be found in the publication series)
  - Merit administrative (Box 1)
    (includes UMnet files)
  - Key administrative documents (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors
    - 1968-1969
      - Minutes (Box 1)
    - 1972-1976
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - 1974-1976
      - Announcements and Agendas (Box 1)
    - 1977-1979
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Income tax exemption 1978 (Box 1)
    - 1979-1984
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - Minutes (Box 2)
    - 1985-1986
      - Agendas (Box 2)
      - Computer conferencing 1986 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - 1985-1988
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - Minutes (Box 2)
    - 1988
      - Meeting, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Subcommittee 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - 1989
      - Meeting, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1990
      - Conference call (Box 2)
    - 1991-1992
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - Retreat group (Box 2)
      - Strategic planning retreat October 1992 (Box 2)
    - 1993-1994
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - 1995-1996
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - 1997-1998
      - Agendas/meeting notices (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Business plan 1999 (Box 3)
  - Bylaws 1988 (Box 3)
  - Chronological file 1993-1995, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Committees
    - Ad-hoc telephone rates monitor committee 1976-1978 (Box 3)
    - Computer policy subcommittee on ARPA interconnection 1973 (Box 3)
    - Director's Advisory Committee
      - 1971-1987, 10 folders (Box 3)
    - Michigan Inter-University Committee on Information Systems (MICIS)
      - General 1971-1973 (Box 4)
      - Agendas/meeting notices 1968-1987, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Correspondence 1973-1989, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Facilities and resources database 1974-1977 (Box 4)
      - Hubbard (Executive Director, Wayne State University) files 1966-1970 (Box 4)
      - Membership list 1979-1981 (Box 4)
      - Minutes 1969-1988, 6 folders (Box 4)
      - State Data Center Program
        - General (Box 4)
        - Correspondence and general information 1977-1979 (Box 4)
        - Meeting agendas and summaries 1979-1981, 1987 (Box 4)
    - NetFuture 1987 (Box 4)
    - Subcommittee on Administrative Computer Services 1975-1981 (Box 4)
    - Supercomputer subcommittee 1982-1986, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - UM computer policy committee 1973 (Box 5)
    - User facilities committee 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - Contracts
    - Applied Dynamics
      - Proposal 1970 (Box 5)
      - Official contract 1970-1972 (Box 5)
      - Subcontract 1970 (Box 5)
      - Revised subcontract 1970 (Box 5)
    - Merit-University contracts 1970 (Box 5)
    - Premonitia agreement 2001 (Box 5)
  - Copyright 1971 (Box 5)
  - Financial
    - Budget
      - 1971/1972-1973/1974, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - 1977/1978-1980/1981, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1972-1973 (Box 5)
      - Fiscal agent correspondence 1970-1974 (Box 5)
    - Government financial matters
      - Correspondence 1972-1973 (Box 5)
      - House and Senate Fiscal Agencies Appropriations process 1973 (Box 5)
      - Michigan House Fiscal Agency 1973-1974 (Box 5)
      - Program Budget Evaluation System (PBES) 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - NSF allocations 1971-1973 (Box 5)
    - Reports and summaries
      - Annual statistical and financial summaries 1973-1987 (Box 5)
      - Funding reports 1969-1976 (Box 5)
      - Network billing summaries 1972-1975, 1984-1987 (Box 5)
      - Quarterly balance of payments 1984-1992 (Box 5)
  - License agreement (Box 5)
  - Meeting notes (Box 5)
    (Aupperle?)
  - Membership 1984-1987 (Box 5)
  - Memos
    - Indices: CCOS, F&RG, HDG, ND (Box 6)
    - Assembler (ASM) 1970 (Box 6)
    - Communications Computer Operating System (CCOS) 1970-1978, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Facilities and Resources Group (F&RG) 1976-1979 (Box 6)
    - Hardware Design Group (HDG) 1974 (Box 6)
    - Hardware Specifications and Selections (HSS) 1970 (Box 6)
    - Merit User Consultants (MC) 1977-1980 (Box 6)
    - Minutes (MIN) 1970-1975 (Box 6)
    - Network-miscellaneous (MISC) 1970-1983, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Network Design (ND)
      - Notes (Box 6)
      - 1969-1989, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Request for Comment (RFC) (Box 6)
    - Software Modification Proposal (SMP) 1977 (Box 6)
    - Telephonics (TEL) 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Network appraisal 1974-1976 (Box 7)
  - Organizational charts 1970 (Box 7)
  - Plans 1973 (Box 7)
  - Policies and practices 1978-1987 (Box 7)
  - President's reports 1969-1975 (Box 7)
  - Projects and proposals
    - Project lists (Box 7)
    - Foundations (Box 7)
    - Eli Lilly proposal 1973 (Box 7)
    - GateD 1995-1996
      - General (Box 7)
      - GateD consortium (Box 7)
      - Analysis of GateD (Box 7)
    - Hughes project 1997 (Box 7)
    - Internet Performance Measurement and Analysis project (IPMA) (Box 7)
    - Kresge Foundation proposal 1977 (Box 7)
    - Merit 1967-1968
      - Proposal summary, first and second revisions (Box 8)
      - No.5, Starks and Bell (Box 8)
      - No.6, Vinsonhaler (Box 8)
      - No.8, Katz (Box 8)
      - No.15, Erickson (Box 8)
      - No.16, Slavens (Box 8)
      - No.18, Kirks-Gulgas (Box 8)
      - No.19, Erlich-Vogel (Box 8)
      - No.21, Falk (Box 8)
    - Michigan Virtual Automotive College (MVAC) 1997 (Box 8)
    - MITRE/Inter-Domain Routing Protocol (IDRP) 1995 (Box 8)
    - Multi-threaded, Distributed Routing Technology (MRT) 1993-1997 (Box 8)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF)
      - Proposal 1968 (Box 8)
        (draft)
      - Addendum 1969 (Box 8)
      - Sharing of technical information 1974 (Box 8)
      - Request for ARPAnet connection 1985 (Box 8)
    - San Diego Supercomputer Center Satellite
      - 1985 (Box 8)
      - 1986 (Box 8)
      - 1988 (Box 8)
      - Blueprints and correspondence (Box 8)
      - Steering committee (Box 8)
    - Teacher Technology Initiative 2000-2001 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes, memos (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous proposals (Box 8)
  - Proposed organizational changes 1973 (Box 8)
  - Publicity/press
    - Articles (Box 9)
    - Brochure 1970-1971 (Box 9)
    - Marketing 1988 (Box 9)
    - Publicity 1970-1977 (Box 9)
  - Seminars and presentations
    - Berlin presentation 1974 (Box 9)
    - Board of Regents 1980 (Box 9)
    - Computer network seminar 1972 (Box 9)
    - Data communications (Box 9)
    - Executive Officers seminar, Holbrook 1982 (Box 9)
    - International Conference on Communications (ICC), "Merit computer network experiences" paper 1975 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous presentations 1970s (Box 9)
    - Research Advisory Council 1982 (Box 9)
    - Seminars
      - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
      - 1979 (Box 9)
    - Technical Seminar II 1982 (Box 9)
  - Technical files
    - 6500 interface documents, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      (includes photograph)
    - Asynchronous communications (Box 9)
    - Hardware acceptance tests
      - General 1972 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - Necessary stimuli to encourage network service (Box 9)
    - Network exchange resource mechanism 1972-1974
      - General (Box 9)
      - Computer use exchange policy (Box 9)
      - Network resource charge (Box 9)
    - Protocols Manual 1979 (Box 9)
      (preliminary version)
    - User's memos 1979-1989 (Box 9)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series (15 linear ft., 1970-2000) has been kept in its original order and is therefore arranged in three different configurations: by date, by topic, and by type. For general background and administrative correspondence, researchers should consult the correspondence arranged by date. Special projects and specialized topics can be found in the topical arrangement. And technical information can be found in the correspondence by type (e.g. Network Operations and Technical Support).
  - By date
    - 1970-1978, 17 folders (Box 10)
    - 1979-1995, 19 folders (Box 11)
  - By topic
    - Ann Arbor District Library 1996 (Box 12)
    - Bentley Historical Library 1990, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Canadian Internet (CANET) 1989-1994 (Box 12)
    - CoNDUIT 1995-1996
      - General (Box 12)
      - 1995 (Box 12)
      - 1996 (Box 12)
      - All-team meeting July 26, 1995 (Box 12)
    - Corporation for Regional and Enterprise Networking (CREN) 1992-1994
      - General (Box 12)
      - CREN/ADP Autonet Dial-in Service (Box 12)
      - CREN virtual seminar (Box 12)
      - CREN III/Bitnet (Box 12)
        (old)
      - CREN 1989-1992 (Box 12)
        (Bitnet/Csnet)
      - Bitnet merger (Box 12)
    - DECnet 1988-1989 (Box 12)
    - E-mail migration 1992 (Box 13)
    - FARNET 1988, 1994 (Box 13)
    - Federal Networking Council 1990 (Box 13)
    - GateD 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Government relations
      - 1987-1993, 10 folders (Box 13)
      - 1994-1996, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Great Lakes Information Network 1993-1994
      - Council of Great Lakes Governors
        - General (Box 14)
        - Meeting (Box 14)
      - Midwest Summit on Information Technology 1993 (Box 14)
    - Macomb/Oakland proposal (MOANET) 1995 (Box 14)
    - Michigan Collegiate Telecommunications Association (MiCTA) 1994-1998 (Box 14)
    - Michigan Information Network (MIN) 1995-1998 (Box 14)
    - Michigan Telecommunications Act 1995 (Box 14)
    - Rural data 1993-1994 (Box 14)
    - Samors, Robert 1992-1994 (Box 14)
    - State of Michigan
      - Dept. of Commerce 1984-1988 (Box 15)
      - Dept. of Education. Ad hoc telecommunications planning and advocacy group 1993-1994 (Box 15)
      - Library of Michigan, State of Michigan file 1996 (Box 15)
      - Michigan Technology Transfer Network 1983-1987 (Box 15)
      - Networking 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Northeast Michigan Consortium 1984-1985 (Box 15)
      - Dept. of Public Health 1984-1991 (Box 15)
      - Technology and Telecommunications Planning and Advocacy Group (TTPAG) 1993-1994
        - Dept. of Education (Box 15)
          (networking)
        - Education Technology Advisory Group (ETAG) (Box 15)
        - Veronica Johnson, UM State of Michigan Office (Box 15)
    - UMNet
      - 1983-1985 (Box 15)
      - Technical staff (UTS) (Box 15)
      - X.25 host attachment (Box 15)
    - University of Michigan
      - Library communications 1984-1989, 6 folders (Box 15)
      - Michigan Council of Library Directors 1986-1989 (Box 15)
    - Wayne State Computer Policy Committee 1974 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - By type
    - Hardware Engineering/Support
      - General (Box 16)
      - 1990-2000, 11 folders (Box 16)
    - Information Services
      - General (Box 16)
      - 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - 1992-2000, 12 folders (Box 17)
    - Net@edu
      - 1999-2000, 8 folders (Box 17)
    - Nethard (Box 18)
      - 1984-1988, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Netsoft
      - 1984-1988, 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Network Managers
      - 1989-1992, 4 folders (Box 18)
      - 1993-1996, 11 folders (Box 19)
      - 1997-2000, 16 folders (Box 20)
    - Network Operations (Box 21)
      - 1989, 2 folders
        - NSFNET Blue Architecture (Box 21)
      - 1990 (January-June) (Box 21)
      - 1991-1992, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Software Engineering (Box 22)
      - General (Box 22)
      - 1990-1991, 7 folders (Box 22)
      - 1992, 2 folders
        - RIF -- terminal servers (Box 22)
      - 1993-2000, 9 folders (Box 22)
    - Technical Support (Box 23)
      - 1989-1994, 13 folders (Box 23)
      - 1995-2000, 12 folders (Box 24)
- Networks
  The Networks series (21 linear ft., 1984-1998) consists of records of the various networks Merit either created, managed or took an active role in, including NSFNET, MichNet, UMNet, MITN, CICNET, and FARNET. The largest portion of the series consists of records documenting Merit's involvement in managing the NSFNET. Records in the NSFNET subseries consist of reports, administrative materials, projects and proposals, contracts and amendments, and press. Other files (mainly correspondence) cover ANS/Valuga, CICNET, FARNET, and the Routing Arbiter.
  - Michigan Technology Network (MITN)
    - 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Michnet
    - Business plan 1990 (Box 25)
    - High Speed connections proposal 1996
      - Correspondence and papers (Box 25)
      - Proposal to NSF (Box 25)
      - 1996-2001, 20 folders (Box 25)
    - Regional network provider proposal 1993 (Box 25)
    - Sales training (Box 25)
  - UMNET
    - Organization and background 1983 (Box 25)
    - Overview of Merit/UMNet evolution 1983 (Box 25)
    - Developments 1983 (Box 25)
  - NSFNET
    - Administrative
      - ARPANET (Box 26)
      - Correspondence (Box 26)
      - Executive Committee
        - E-mail and miscellaneous 1992-1995 (Box 26)
        - Press kit information 1989 (Box 26)
        - Executive Committee members 1990 (Box 26)
        - Conference call agendas 1991-1992 (Box 26)
        - Meeting agendas and minutes 1990-1994 (Box 26)
        - Meetings
          - 1988-1995, 26 folders (Box 26)
      - IBM meetings 1987, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - International access
        - 1989
          - George Krembs NSFNET international access file (Box 27)
        - 1990-1991, 4 folders (Box 27)
      - ISO migration 1988 (Box 27)
      - Managers meetings
        - 1988-1990, 14 folders (Box 27)
      - Meetings with Jack Drescher 1988 (Box 27)
      - Network Control Center 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Network diagrams 1992-1993 (Box 27)
      - NSF Division Advisory Panel 1988 (Box 27)
      - Reference materials 1987-1991 (Box 27)
      - Routing maps 1989 (Box 27)
      - Site manual 1991 (Box 27)
      - Technical compliance 1991-1994 (Box 27)
      - Update meeting minutes (Box 28)
        - 1988-1989, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Agreements
      - National Science Foundation
        - Grant background materials (Box 28)
        - Project solicitation 1987 (Box 28)
        - Proposal 1987 (Box 28)
        - Proposal budget (Box 28)
        - NSF/Merit negotiations 1987 (Box 28)
        - Cooperative agreement 1987 (Box 28)
        - Award documents 1987-1993 (Box 28)
      - MCI/Merit agreement 1987
        - General (Box 28)
        - Correspondence and other documents (Box 28)
      - IBM/Merit agreement, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - UM/Merit agreement 1987-1995
        - Background/drafts (Box 28)
        - Memo of understanding (Box 28)
        - CICNET supplement (Box 28)
      - Michigan Strategic Fund
        - General/correspondence (Box 28)
        - Materials to MSF for grant (Box 28)
        - MSF resolution, 1922-111 (Box 28)
      - Non-disclosure agreements 1988 (Box 28)
      - Remote site agreements 1988-1991 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous agreements (Box 29)
    - Amendments
      - Cooperative agreements (Box 29)
        (contains agreements for amendments 1-11)
      - Amendment 1: Cooperative agreement (Box 29)
      - Amendment 2: Fiscal year 1989 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 3: Fiscal year 1990 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 4: Added nodes and speed 1990
        - General (Box 29)
        - Expansion solicitation (Box 29)
        - Expansion proposal (Box 29)
        - Expansion proposal revision (Box 29)
        - Expansion proposal final (Box 29)
      - Amendment 5: Added nodes and travel expenses 1990 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 6: T3 1991 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 7: Fiscal year 1991 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 8: T3 connection to NASA sites, statement of purpose, NSF NASA site (Box 29)
      - Amendment 9: Fiscal year 1992 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 10: DARPA connectivity 1992
        - General (Box 29)
        - DARPA connectivity to NSFNET (Box 29)
      - Amendment 11: Extension 1993
        - General (Box 29)
        - Extension documents, 3 folders (Box 29)
        - Division of Research Development and Administration, University of Michigan (DRDA) proposal approval forms (Box 29)
        - Solicitation/request for cooperative agreement extension 1992 (Box 29)
        - Extension proposal 1992 (Box 29)
        - NSF response, 5 folders (Box 29)
        - Form 7471 (Box 29)
        - ANS voice cutover from T1 (Box 29)
      - Amendment 12: Subcontract to ANS and change to general terms and conditions (Box 29)
      - Amendment 13: Fiscal year 1994
        - General (Box 29)
        - Proposal to NSF, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Amendment 14: Fiscal year 94.2 extension 1994
        - 94.2 extension (Box 29)
        - Acceptable use policy (Box 29)
      - Amendments, 14, 15, 16 binder with important documents (Box 29)
      - Amendment 15: Transition 1994
        - General (Box 30)
        - Budget (Box 30)
        - Funding (Box 30)
        - Meeting (Box 30)
        - Negotiations (Box 30)
        - Proposal, 2 folders (Box 30)
        - Recompete
          - 1993 (Box 30)
          - ANS (Box 30)
          - CICNET (Box 30)
        - Response to NSF with revised budgets, 3 folders (Box 30)
        - Staffing (Box 30)
        - Subcontract, Merit/ANS (Box 30)
      - Amendment 16: Transition proposal
        - General (Box 30)
        - Budget material (Box 30)
      - Amendment 17: Transition extension 1995 (Box 30)
    - Events/Occasions
      - Luncheon and NOC tour 1988 (Box 30)
      - Seminars
        - Advanced topics seminar
          (See Box 55 for videotapes of the seminar)
          - 1989 (Box 30)
          - 1992 (Box 30)
        - Networking/Internetworking seminar